Are you not a lines guy or gal?
Are straight edges and getting that really nice straight line just difficult for you to get?
Well, there's a nice technique you can use which is called masking.
It basically involves obviously some painting but also some tape applied to your canvas.
First, take off a couple strips of masking tape.
Now, make sure that the tape you use is either artist tape or is like a type of, most masking tapes should be fine but you don't want duct tape because you could actually rip the surface of your canvas or actually, just your entire canvas in two because that stuff is industrial strength stick.
You put your masking tape on here.
Now, we're going to fill around here with paint.
And just go nuts on this, you know.
You want to make sure that there are not little white barriers kind of sneaking around here and escaping your painting brush.
Now, after we've done this, and we're satisfied and we're really happy with the painting layer we have on here, the tape is surrounded so we don't have to worry about if there is any edges we want to get on later on.
Now, we're going to take the tape off.
Some people wait for the tape to dry.
It depends kind of on what you're doing.
Be very gentle and pull away the first strip.
Now, let's pull away the second strip.
And you can see, voila, those wonderful, straight lines you've always wanted.
Here you go.
You can do this when you can combine different layers of paint or maybe you're just going to use this as a guideline.
Now you can fill this in yourself.
You can do multiple layers of this, getting really cool cascading, very nice, straight lined effects for you paintings.